Finding Aid for Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (University of Michigan-Wayne State University) records, 1949-1975
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (University of Michigan-Wayne State University) records 1949-1975
Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (University of Michigan-Wayne State University).
1 linear foot
8747 Bimu C542 2
Organization founded jointly by the University of Michigan and Wayne State University to encourage practical education and research in all areas of industrial relations. Files from the University of Michigan office, including executive board records, unpublished papers, and miscellaneous topical files; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the Institute (donor no. 3794 ) and came to the library in 1986.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations was founded in the Spring of 1957 under the joint auspices of the University of Michigan and Wayne State University. Its objective is to encourage practical education and research in all areas of industrial relations.
The Institute's records measure one linear foot and date from 1949 to 1975. They consist of a scattering of materials, arbitrarily arranged into a single topical file. Of most interest are the executive board records (1957-1960; 1966-1969) and a few unpublished papers regarding aspects of labor relations in Michigan.
Subjects:
Industrial relations--United States.; Labor--Michigan.
- Topical File, 1949-1975
  - Allen, Donna, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod, S. J., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Barkin, Solomon, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Certificates, ca. 1958 (Box 1)
  - Community Services (Box 1)
  - Councils
    - Community, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
    - Faculty, 1957-1960 (Box 1)
    - Labor Advisory, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Executive Board
    - 1957-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1966-1969 (Box 1)
  - Ferman, Lou, and Scott Harvey, "Job Retraining in Michigan," 1964 (Box 1)
  - French Trade Union Development Team, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Hunter, Woodrow, "Pre-Retirement Report," 1959 (Box 1)
  - Italian Trade Union Development Team, 1959-1960, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Labor School Brochures, 1965-1975 (Box 1)
  - Marcus, Philip M., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, University of
    - Bureau of Industrial Relations, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Institute for Social Research, 1949-1956 (Box 1)
  - Pikulinski, Jerome, "Use of Organizational Constructs to Shape the Behavior of Semi-Professional Trainers in Detroit," 1967 (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Rehmus, Charles M. and Anita W. Schoomaker, "Public Safety 'Final Offer' Arbitration in Michigan," 1974 (Box 1)
  - Sexton, Brendon, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
  - Social Security Conferences (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Photos of labor conferences at the University of Michigan, 1957-1964 (Box 1)